A Guide to the William H. Whyte papers FA272
Rockefeller Archive Center
William H. Whyte papers
1944-1993
Rockefeller Archive Center
Whyte, William H.
FA272
16 Cubic Feet
Appraisal
October 1990 (Vol. 162 No. 10) and November 1990 (Vol. 162 No. 11) of House & Garden Magazine were discarded
Separated Materials
Special format items (audio, film, video, digital media, library materials, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Arrangement
The William H. Whyte papers are divided into three series: 1. Projects and Research, 2. Personal, and 3. Audiovisual Materials.
The papers primarily remain in original order, as received.
Whyte grouped his files under various headings or categories, but in many cases the relationship between contents and heading is ambiguous or unapparent. A number of the files also carry whimsical titles, further complicating the task of appraising the contents. In processing Whyte's papers, files have been grouped under his designated headings, with only occasional slight modification of headings or titles for clarity. In a few cases, headings were added to improve order.
In navigating Whyte's papers, it is important to recognize the fluid nature of his categories, titles, and file contents. Materials relating to the same topic may be filed under different headings. For instance, materials relating to the "Street Life Project" are located not only in the Street Life Project section, but also among the Films (General), Lincoln Center, Pedestrian Flows, Plaza Film, Plaza Reports, Plaza Studies, Social Life of the Street, and Vehicular Studies categories, among others. This lack of consolidation, true to the original order of the files, sheds light on Whyte's work process as well as his organizational style.
The distinctions between sections with similar titles are also vague or minor. This is true of the Plaza Report and Plaza Studies headings, as well as the Films (General), Plaza Film, and New Film files. Additionally, some files maintain catch-all headings or headings that were meaningful to Whyte which may not be immediately comprehensible within the given context. Such ambiguity is exemplified by categories such as Books and Films and Grist.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
The papers of urbanist, journalist, author and people-watcher William H. Whyte, which date from the mid-1940s to the early 1990s, relate primarily to his projects and research. The collection contains a vast amount of material on Whyte's work with easements as well as his various film projects. Materials on studies of pedestrian behavior and city dynamics conducted as part of the "Street Life Project", including Whyte's research on city social life as well as human and vehicular movement patterns, are also a prominent part of the collection.
Whyte, William H.
- Projects and Research, 1
  Scope and Contents
  Projects and Research is by far the largest series, which contains clippings, charts, correspondence, images, graphs, notes and reports related to Whyte's studies.
  Within Projects and Research, in addition to individual files, there are several larger categories, including Pedestrian studies, Vehicular studies, Plaza studies, and Easements. There are also specific locations which Whyte studied or about which he was consulted, including Bryant Park, Greenacre Foundation and Park, Lincoln Center, and Penn Station/Madison Square Garden in New York City.
  - Architects, 1969-1987
    - General, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Architects: Big Thinking, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Architects: Big Thinking, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes materials written in French.
    - Architects: Urban Design, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Architectural Prose, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Capitol Land Company: Review of Architects, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Report: Study of the Profession of Landscape Architecture, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Venturi: Radical Architects, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art: Anatomy of a Bluff, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Battery Park City: South Gardens, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bench Placement, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Books and Films (General), 1954-1989
    - Arcades, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Benjamin Franklin Award, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Jerusalem, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Film, Writing, and Exhibit Promotions: Local Tie-Ins, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Materials concern Whyte's film "City Spaces, Human Places" and his exhibit on Blank Walls, among other topics.
    - Reviews of Book and Film Versions of "The Social Life of Small Urban Spaces", 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Requests by Individuals and Institutions for Whyte's Films, Television Appearances, and Writings, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bryant Park, 1963-1986
    - General, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hartford Versus Central Park, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - New York Public Library: Extra Maps, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - New York Public Library: Recommendations, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - New York Public Library: Use Patterns, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Physical Changes, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Programming, Maintenance, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Rockefeller, Laurance S., Memos, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Includes copies of memos from Whyte to Laurance S. Rockefeller concerning his research on urban spaces and recentralization. Correspondence concerns the New York Landmark Conservancy, and the landmark status of the Ansonia Hotel and Rockefeller Plaza and Channel Gardens. There is no specific reference to Bryant Park.
    - Ticketing: Notes, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Ticketing: Text, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Business Improvement Districts, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - City Book, 1987-1993
    - Center of the City: Lexington Avenue: Elevations, Blockfront 57th Street - 58th Street, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Original for 37A - Center of the City, 2014:FA272:001
        Conditions Governing Access
        Due to the oversize nature and potentially brittle condition of this material, special arrangements may be required in order to view materials. Individual items may be restricted due to preservation concerns.
        Separated Materials
        Large plan labeled "Original for 37A- Center of the City"
        Special format items (audio, film, video, digital media, library materials, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
    - Center of the City: Outline, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Center of the City, Chapter Notes: Lexington Avenue and Southwest Corner of 59th Street: Fast Brown and Slow Blue, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - City: Rediscovering the Center: Advertising, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - City: Rediscovering the Center: Doubleday Royalties, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1969-1990
    - General, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Case Histories: Public Housing, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Magazine and Newspaper Articles, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - New Megas, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - New York City Planning, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Recent, 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Urban Shopping Centers, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Concourses and Skyways, 1982-1999
    - General, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Illustrations, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Publication Details, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Conferences, 1958-1979
    - The Conference Bums, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - "I Was a Conference Bum": Conference Proceedings, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Colonial Williamsburg: Peacock Hill Seminar, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Conservation Foundation, 1971-1988
    - Presidency, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Successful Communities Advisory Committee, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Dallas, 1982-1985
    - Color Prints: Dallas City Hall Plaza, Undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Project, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Questionnaires, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Report on Downtown and City Hall Plaza, Undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Report to the City Council on the Dallas City Hall Plaza and central business district spaces.
    - Seminar, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Dayton Main Street Project, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Map of Downtown Dayton, 2014:FA272:002
  - Easements, 1961-1990
    Arrangement
    Alphabetical, then Regional
    - General: Articles, 1966-1986 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - General: Articles, Clippings, 1975-1986 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - General: Articles, Transactions, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - General: Brochures, Notes, 1973-1982 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - General: Proposals, Memos, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Additional Studies, 1976-1986 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Adverse Reports, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Conservation and Tax Legislation, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Court Opinions, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Current Easement Programs, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Deed Forms, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Easement History, Undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Effects on Land Values, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Ells, Stephen, Study, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Facade Easement Programs, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Golf Clubs, 1967 (Folder 5, Box 70)
    - Green Belts, 1957-1968 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Housing and Home Finance Agency: Open-Space Land Program, 1961-1966 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Land Trust Articles, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 73)
      Includes articles written by Whyte
    - Meetings with the IRS, 1971-1986 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Merrywood Case, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Migratory Bird Commission: Wetland, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - National Park Service, 1965-1973 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 78)
      File consists of one clipping.
    - Nature Conservancy, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - RFGs: Provisions Regarding Scenic Enjoyment, Undated (Box 5, Folder 80)
      General
      The meaning of the abbreviation RFG is not explained.
    - The Sacred Writings: Articles, Talk, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 81)
      Includes talk by William H. Whyte on "Open Space and Retroactive Planning" for the American Society of Planning Officials, May 20, 1958.
    - Specific Programs, 1976-1986 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Tax Rulings, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Transfer of Development Rights, 1977-1986 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Use to Guarantee Cluster: Open Spaces, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Valuation: Article, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Valuation and Costs, 1955-1967 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Woodlawn Trustees Case, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 88)
      - A part of Brandywine Hundred, New Castle County, DE, and parts of Birmingham and Concord Townships, Delaware County, PA, for Woodlawn Trustees, Inc., 2014:FA272:003
        Oversized map.
      - A part of Brandywine Hundred, New Castle County, DE, for Woodlawn Trustees, Inc., 2014:FA272:004
    - California: General, 1970-1976 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - California: San Francisco Area, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Connecticut: General, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Connecticut: Connecticut River, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Connecticut: Connecticut River, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Connecticut: Farm Tax Legislation, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Connecticut: Nature Conservancy, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Connecticut: Open Space Report, 1963-1987 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Connecticut: Open Space Reports and Follow-Up, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Connecticut: Tax Bills, 1962-1967 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Maine: General, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Maine: Maine Coast Trust, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Maryland: Annapolis Easement Effort, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Massachusetts: Massachusetts Experience, 1961-1974 (Box 7, Folder 102)
      - Open Space Reservations owned as of October 30, 1960; Sudbury Valley Trustees, Inc., Wayland, MA, 2014:FA272:005
    - Massachusetts: Watershed Council, Inc., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - Minnesota: General, 1965-1969 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Missouri: Ozark Riverways, 1961-1963 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - New Jersey: General, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - New Jersey: Open Space Policy Commission, 1968-1973 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - New Jersey: Transfer Development Rights, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - New York: General, 1969-1985 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - New York: Fishing Rights, 1965-1974 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - New York: Legislation, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - New York: Morgan - Hyde Park, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - New York Landmarks Conservancy: General, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - New York Landmarks Conservancy: Brochure, Proposals, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - New York Landmarks Conservancy: Federal Tax Concerns, 1969-1985 (Box 8, Folder 115)
    - New York Landmarks Conservancy: Forms, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - New York Landmarks Conservancy: India House, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 117)
    - New York Landmarks Conservancy: More on Easements, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - New York State Legislation, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - Ohio: Committee for a Country Common, 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 120)
      - Master Plan for a Country Common, Yellow Springs, OH, 2014:FA272:006
      - Open Space Acquisition and Development Plan, Yellow Springs, OH, 2014:FA272:007
    - Pennsylvania: General, 1974-1980 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Pennsylvania: Brandywine Conservancy, 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 122)
      - Proposed Ownership Residential Sites, Buck and Doe Run Valley Farms, Inc., Chester County, PA, 2014:FA272:008
    - Pennsylvania: Chester County, 1965-1976 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Pennsylvania: French and Pickering Creeks Trust, 1973-1985 (Box 8, Folder 124)
      - Open Space and Historic Preservation, Watersheds of the French and Pickering Creeks, 2014:FA272:009
      - County Interim Plan, Chester County, PA, 2014:FA272:010
    - Pennsylvania: Philadelphia Conservationists, Inc., 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 125)
    - Vermont: General, 1966-1974 (Box 9, Folder 126)
    - Virginia: General, 1966-1974 (Box 9, Folder 127)
    - Washington, D.C.: Potomac River, 1961-1968 (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - Wisconsin Experience, 1961-1970 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - Wyoming: General, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - Wyoming: Jackson Hole, 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - Wyoming: Jackson Hole, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 132)
  - End of the Exodus, 1976-1988
    - Article, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - Additional Materials, 1982-1987 (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Background, 1979-1988 (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - Clippings: 1970s, 1972-1978 (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - Clippings: 1980s, 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Comparisons, 1976-1987 (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - Maps, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 139)
    - New York: Letters, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    - New York: Maps, Undated (Box 10, Folder 141)
      - Map of Stamford, CT, 2014:FA272:011
      - Map of Stamford, CT, 2014:FA272:012
      - Map of Greenwich, CT, 2014:FA272:013
      - Map of Stamford, CT, 2014:FA272:014
    - New York: Relocation Tabulations, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 142)
    - New York City and the Corporation Exodus, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 143)
    - New York Times Op Ed Piece: Computations, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 144)
    - Travel, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 145)
      File contains October 1983 Regional Plan Association Technical Report on "The Effect of Headquarters Office Locations on Travel."
  - Films (General), 1980-1989
    - Basic Footage: Topic Finder, Undated (Box 10, Folder 146)
    - Log: Negative - Positive, Undated (Box 10, Folder 147)
    - New York and Tokyo, Undated (Box 10, Folder 148)
    - NOVA Narration: "City Spaces, Human Places", c. 1981, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 149)
    - NOVA Program: "City Spaces, Human Places", 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 150)
    - Playground Film Notes, Undated (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - Social Life of Small Urban Spaces: Copyright, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - Social Life of Small Urban Spaces: Publicity, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 153)
  - Greenacre Foundation and Park, 1980-1986
    - 805 Third Avenue: Building Plans, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 154)
    - 805 Third Avenue: Testimony, Correspondence, 1970-1984 (Box 11, Folder 155)
    - Easement: General, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 156)
    - Easement: Report, 1983-1988 (Box 11, Folder 157)
    - Greenacre Sun: Easement Memos, 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 158)
    - Greenacre Sun: Statement by Whyte, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 159)
      - Proposed Shadow Diagram, 805 Third Avenue, New York, NY, 2014:FA272:015
    - Greenacre Sun: Study Maps, Undated (Box 11, Folder 160)
  - Grist, 1964-1990
    - Barrie, David: London Film, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 161)
    - Beverly Hills, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 162)
    - Big Thinking: Grist for the Mill, 1960-1983 (Box 11, Folder 163)
    - Bruner Seminar on Excellence in Urban Spaces, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 164)
      Original folder entitled "Mailing Maps."
    - Dimensions, Undated (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Effect of Television on Behavior, Undated (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - London, 1971-1989 (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - Moss, Mitchell L., Articles, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 168)
    - New Jersey: Carnegie Center, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 169)
    - New Grist, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 170)
    - New Series or Special: The Street, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 171)
    - Paris, 1975-1979 (Box 11, Folder 172)
    - Prose, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 173)
    - South Cove, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 174)
      Concerning south gardens at Battery Park City.
    - Street Life, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 175)
      Discussion of street trading in Johannesburg, South Africa.
  - Hudson River Valley Commission, 1967-1972
    - General, 1967-1971 (Box 12, Folder 176)
      - Photo reproduction by Hudson River Valley Commission, 2014:FA272:016
        Oversized photo reproduction by Hudson River Valley Commission. Also found in Box 13, Folder 189.
    - Critical Areas, 1970-1974 (Box 12, Folder 177)
      - Project Review Flow Chart, 2014:FA272:017
        Oversized project review flow chart.
    - Memos, Minutes, Printed Matter, 1968-1972 (Box 12, Folder 178)
  - Landscapes, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 179)
  - Lincoln Center, 1980-1981
    - General, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 180)
    - Illustrations, Undated (Box 12, Folder 181)
    - Project, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 182)
    - Reports, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 183)
    - Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 184)
    - Sighting Maps, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 185)
    - Sighting Maps, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 186)
  - Municipal Art Society, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 187)
  - Napa Community Redevelopment Agency, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 188)
  - New Film, 1970-1979
    - Aerial Photography, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 189)
      - Photo reproduction by Hudson River Valley Commission, 2014:FA272:018
        Oversized photo reproduction by Hudson River Valley Commission. Also found in Box 12, Folder 176.
    - Film Technique: Notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 190)
    - Historical Photos, 1988, undated (Box 13, Folder 191)
      Includes materials regarding "The Social Life of Small Urban Spaces."
    - Log of Cassettes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 192)
    - Notes, c. 1984 (Box 13, Folder 193)
      Includes materials relating to the U.S. Photo Survey and planned "CitySeen" exhibit at the New-York Historical Society.
    - Prostitute Community: Script, Undated (Box 13, Folder 194)
    - Soapboxers (Annotated) and Layman's Guide, Undated (Box 13, Folder 195)
      Description and remarks on filmed interactions. Includes analysis on Cooperative Arguments.
    - Street Sounds: Tape, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 196)
      Notes on recordings of conversations and street musicians.
    - Time Lapse Methodology, 1971-1979 (Box 13, Folder 197)
  - Old Westbury: Blankman, Norman, Cluster Housing Project, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 198)
  - "Organization Man" Revisited, 1985-1990
    - General, 1957-1985 (Box 13, Folder 199)
    - General, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - Book: Sales Figures, Chart of Mail, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 201)
    - Citations (Box 13, Folder 202)
    - Grist: Economics, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 203)
    - Leinberger, Paul: Article, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 204)
    - Leinberger, Paul: Project, 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 205)
    - Mcinnis, Raymond G., Study, 1985-1989 (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - New Preface, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - Wives, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 208)
  - Osborn, Robert, 1952-1954 (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Correspondence - Watercolor, 1952; 2014:FA272:019
      Oversized correspondence, approximately 11" by 14", postmarked 1952 October 29.
    - Undated letter with watercolor illustration, 2014:FA272:020
      Oversized undated letter with watercolor illustration, approximately 11" by 14".
  - Paley Park: Weather and Food Sales Charts, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 210)
  - Pedestrian Flows, 1973-1986
    - Analysis: 53rd Street: Madison Avenue - Fifth Avenue, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 211)
      - 53rd Street and Madison Avenue, 2014:FA272:021
        Oversized chart.
    - Analysis: Fifth Avenue: 45th Street - 46th Street, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 212)
    - Analysis: Madison Avenue: 45th Street - 46th Street, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 213)
    - Analysis: Madison Avenue: 48th Street - 49th Street, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 214)
    - Analysis: Madison Avenue: 51st Steet - 52nd Street, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 215)
    - Analysis: Madison Avenue: 54th Street - 55th Street, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 216)
    - Analysis: Madison Avenue: 57th Street - 58th Street, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 217)
    - Categories: Lexington Avenue and Sixth Avenue, Undated (Box 14, Folder 218)
    - Counts: General, 1975-1978 (Box 14, Folder 219)
    - Counts: 60th Street and Third Avenue, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 220)
    - Counts: Grand Central Station, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 221)
    - Counts: Lexington Avenue, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 222)
    - Counts: Nassau Street, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 223)
    - Counts: San Francisco: Market Street, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 224)
    - Counts and Charts: Lexington Avenue, 1974 July 10 (Box 14, Folder 225)
    - Lexington Avenue: Alexander's Doorway, Undated (Box 14, Folder 226)
    - Lexington Avenue: Bloomingdale's and Alexander's Entrance Study, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 227)
    - Lexington Avenue: Southwest Corner of 59th Street, Undated (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - Multi-Purpose Building: 53rd Street, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 229)
      File concerns possible location and design for a new Asia Society building.
      - 53rd Street and Madison Avenue, 2014:FA272:022
    - Pedestrian-Vehicular Imbalance, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 230)
    - Sidewalks: 60th Street and Third Avenue, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - Underground Concourse Study, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 232)
  - Pedestrian Traffic Studies, 1971-1992
    - Annotations, Undated (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - Calcutta, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 234)
      Clipping on Calcutta
    - Contracts, 1971-1977 (Box 14, Folder 235)